



Sarah.Caseberry@gmail.com



+44 7935 374433



28th August 1984



12 Wood Ride, Petts Wood, London, BR5 1PX

PROFILE

Strategist, story teller and problem solver focused on marketing transformation, with a keen interest in omnichannel experiences & emerging technologies. I specialise in helping brands understand their purpose, identifying what their audience needs & why they're the right brand to meet those needs, and how to make it happen.

SKILLS

Strategic Planning and Visioning Problem Solving Process Change Project Management Budgeting Capability Team Management Stakeholder Management Agile Consumer Experience Strategy Digital Marketing Demand Gen Comms Planning Brand Strategy SEO & SEM **Channel Strategy** Performance Marketing **Events** CRM ABM Sales Enablement Audience research and insights Analytics and reporting Data Ecomm & Trade Production Influencer management Data

Freelance experience can be found on the final page

SARAH CASEBERRY

EXPERIENCE



Thredd (formerly GPS) – Head/Director of Digital Marketing October 2021 – present

- Responsible for creation of digital marketing team, one of five key heads brought into the business to set up and build out a new marketing function
- Definition of board-approved integrated marketing strategy including the setting of overall business unit ambitions, objectives, and requirements
- Setting of annual budget, creation of resourcing plan, recruitment of new team from the ground up
- Co-led biggest project undertaken by business to date, developing and launching new brand, name, and website alongside the head of brand
- Responsible for wildly successful brand launch campaign, resulting in more than 1000% increase in traffic to site and 500% increase in enquiries
- Development of roadmap and management of workstreams to put in place all foundational marketing elements including but not limited to:
 - All new martech
 - · Email marketing and CRM programme
 - Lead nurture, sales enablement and ABM
 - Measurement framework and attribution
 - Social and content strategies
 - · Paid media strategy
 - · Content studio
 - · Asset management programme
 - Digital training programme
 - SEO programme
- Day to day running of the digital marketing, senior-leadership BAU, people and team management, reporting to the board on function performance



Britvic PLC – Global Head of Digital, Consumer Experience Hub *May 2020 – June 2021 (maternity cover)*

- Responsible for acceleration of digital and marketing effectiveness, driving customer-centric planning, omnichannel optimisation and transformational process change to unlock growth opportunity and drive net revenue
- Consultant to marketing leads across eight brands (including Tango, London Essence, Robinsons), acting as subject matter expert and all-round strategic support, ensuring customer need and omnichannel experience sits at the heart of all planning
- Point person connecting marketing to other BU's across the business such as ecom, retail, wholesale and trade marketing – collaborating with these functions to ensure they have the tools for success
- Running programme to optimise current presence and performance in retail as well as new product development and exploration of new routes to market – including big four, DTC, out of home, delivery aggregator, Amazon and Amazon Fresh
- Setting up and running enablement programme, uncovering problems and opportunities across the business and finding ways to fix or utilise them – this includes running pilots to prove effectiveness and then scaling globally, putting in place best practice guidelines, toolkits and governance, and procuring necessary martech solutions

VOLUNTEERING

- Trustee, Board of Trustees, Women's Aid, Bromley and Croydon Jan 2019 – present
- Crisis at Christmas volunteer
 2015 present
- General volunteer, homeless support network, London
 2012 – present

INTERESTS

Outside work I like to travel with my family, read at least four books a week, collect and listen to vinyl, watch cozy crime mysteries, bake bread, and write stories.

EDUCATION

2000-2002 Hugh Baird College

- A Level History
- A Level English
- A Level Sociology
- A/S Level Psychology
- AVCE Media and Communications

1995-2000 Chesterfield High School

• 7 GCSE's (A-C)

- Leading project to embed a data driven model by in-housing data streams, bringing in new data streams, and building intuitive dashboards that facilitate real and near time insights
- Development of attribution model to measure impact of online activity on overall brand and business measures and in relation to offline performance
- Responsible for improvement of all customer (b2c and b2b) facing content and creative, ensuring it's made for channel and optimised for objective – management of in-house studio and 3 content managers to facilitate this as well as ownership of 'always-on' social programme
- Supervision of DAM (internal and delivery of assets to third parties such as retailers and trade) and management of direct report who runs day to day and maintenance of the programme
- Build capability of digital marketing within brand teams and across the business, and establish/manage a roster of key agency suppliers



Key Achievements

- Development of team vision and roadmap with buy in from senior stakeholders successful execution of year one of this plan
- Embedded platform optimisation workstream and a new path to purchase model which to date has:
 - driven a 200+% increase in sales in Amazon alone
 - driven revenue growth across all retailers
 - attributed to 10% increase in online share of total sales
 - improved ECI scores (brand presence in retail vs competitor)
- Developed digital strategy process and rolled out across the businesses using agile principles and project management



HP Inc – Head of Digital Marketing & Strategy, and Omnichannel Lead $May\ 2016-May\ 2019$

- Management of the omnichannel transformation project, including issue identification and resolution planning/testing, procurement of resource and martech solutions, embedding and scaling of solutions, to drive optimised customer and consumer experiences across the business
- Responsible for definition of three year integrated digital marketing roadmap & vision, incl. objective/KPI setting, measurement & performance tracking, activation planning & management of \$5m+ budgets
- Management of BAU digital marketing programme, including content and comms, co-marketing, ecommerce acquisition and new RTM, demand gen/ABM and CRM strategy, sales enablement, data programme, event planning, digital agency roster, and line management of 2 subject matter experts (SEO and data)
- Point person between marketing and other vital functions and RTM business units such as ecom, sales, category, trade and channel
- Management of asset and web programme for NPDs throughout gating process, inc. agency briefing, production (inc. leading shoots), best practice brand/style guidelines and web development
- Consultant to marketing campaign leads, acting as the strategy expert in key areas such as comms, digital, omnichannel, performance marketing, etc in order to ensure optimised customer and consumer experiences – also leading training and upskilling of digital capabilities

TOOLS AND SOFTWARE



Adobe Creative Cloud

☑ Google Analytics

Adobe Analytics

M PowerBI

SAP analytics

Salesforce, Eloqua, Pardot

OPAL, Trello, Asana, Jira

Sysomos & Crimson Hexagon

Sprinklr & Buddy Media

Various other Martech solutions



Key Achievements

- New vision and digital roadmap developed for EMEA scaled to global with exec buy in for omnichannel project including required budget and support on aggressive timelines, first half results included:
 - 30% increase in on-time-delivery of assets and content
 - 57% increase in channel 'perfect presence' scores
 - 28% increase in organic search to landing pages
 - 20% increase in direct sales and attributed % increase in SME and enterprise sales
- Set up of editorial newsroom with new agency, including a high profile editor & experienced journalists, now also scaled to global
- Roll out of new campaign briefing & approval process, and new production process & guidelines, both now embedded globally
- Set up marketing dashboards and measurement of online performance, as well as on-going customer research & journey mapping programme



Strategy Director, Gyro London (B2B agency)

Jan – May 2016



Strategy Director, Critical Mass (digital agency)

October 2015 - Jan 2016

Hired into Critical Mass to completely overhaul the agency strategy and digital marketing offering and take ownership of the primary client, HP. Subsequently TUPE'd to Gyro to continue this role at the request of client CMO.



Key Achievements

- Developed and rolled out first EMEA wide digital brand marketing strategy for HP, sold in to all EMEA and country marketing stakeholders
- Developed first EMEA wide content & asset vision for HP spanning owned platforms and ecom as well as channel, trade and sales that resulted in:
 - 47% increase in contacts captured
 - 20% increase in direct sales and attributed % increase in SME and enterprise sales
 - overall improved consideration metrics in platform
- Set up first centralised editorial team for HP and put in place local content leads in 7 countries

OLDER



Lead Strategist, Proximity London (creative agency)

July – October 2015



Strategy Director, VCCP Kin (content & advertising agency) May 2013 – July 2015



Lead Digital and Social Strategist, R/GA (digital agency) Feb 2012 – May 2013



Senior Digital Strategist, 3 Monkeys (PR agency) Jan 2011 – Feb 2012



Senior Marketing Strategist and Global Platform Lead (music agency) Nov 2005 – Jan 2011

Details available upon request

FREELANCE AND CONSULTING



Freelance strategy and omnichannel experience marketing consultant 2010 – present

Freelancing as a strategist and/or marketer for more than a decade, working with big name brands, smaller businesses and agencies. Some examples include:

- Nonsense: clients including Sky, AXA, LFC, Adobe, Cancer Research leading everything from brand strategy to digital and content strategy
- AYS: clients such as RB, Mead Johnson leading research, brand identity, brand purpose projects in China, India and the US
- MomentumABM: clients including Google, Finastra and HP leading global B2B campaign, brand strategy, digital strategy, ABM and sales enablement projects
- Mustard development of brand and digital strategy for new CBD product launch
- Brandcast Health: various clients digital, social and content strategy
- Columns: clients including ADC and Shell, leading brand strategy, content activation, and research
- SYZYGY: global clients such as GSK, Kyocera, Mazda leading digital channel, digital strategy, omnichannel transformation, CX strategy, website UX and build
- Wunderman Thompson: Knight Frank global research project, brand and business strategy
- FKC: Superdrug digital, CRM, paid media and brand strategy
- Unit 9: IQOS global brand strategy, event planning, ROI modelling
- Mollie development of new brand strategy and identity
- White Bear: Kopparberg, Carlsberg brand and channel strategy, sales enablement, digital and content strategy
- Flipside: Gambleaware research, brand and website audit, digital proposal
- Bacardi annual global research piece
- RAPP: various pharma clients digital strategy, UX and web development, omnichannel optimisation, brand strategy